A Guide to the Grand Teton Lodge Company Records FA423
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grand Teton Lodge Company, 1926-1991; 2; 7.5 Cubic Feet 15 boxes
  - New York Office
    - Chorley, Kenneth
      - 1960 (Box 18, Folder 215)
        - Entrance Layout at Jackson Lake Lodge, 1953 October 31; 2003:104:017 (Folder 10)
      - 1961 (1) (Box 18, Folder 216)
      - 1961 (2) (Box 18, Folder 217)
      - 1962 (1) (Box 18, Folder 218)
      - 1962 (2) (Box 18, Folder 219)
      - 1963 (Box 18, Folder 220)
      - 1967 (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - Hoke, Robert L., 1955-1956 (Box 18, Folder 222)
      Public Relations at Jackson Hole Preserve Inc.
    - Hoke, Robert L., 1958-1959, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 223)
    - Layne, Mildred (Correspondence), 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 224)
      Vice President of the Jackson Hole Preserve
      Corporate officer of the Grand Teton Lodge Company
  - Oberhansley, Frank: Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 225)
    Superintendent of Grand Teton National Park
  - Office of Price Stabilization, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 226)
  - Opening: Jackson Lake Lodge, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 227)
    1312
  - Operations: General, 1948, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 228)
  - Operations: General, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - Operations: Estimates, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 230)
  - Operations: Estimates, 1946-1947, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 231)
  - Operations: Estimates, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 232)
  - Operations: Jackson Lake Lodge, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 233)
  - Operations: Jenny Lake Lodge, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - Development of Jenny Lake Lodge (blueprint), 1956 October 12; 2003:104:018 (Folder 10)
  - Operations: Jenny Lake Lodge, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 234 (A))
    Restricted- Confidential Material
  - Operations: Kitchens, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 235)
  - Personnel, 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 236)
  - Personnel, 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 236 A)
    Restricted - Confidential material.
  - Plans and Construction, 1946-1951 (Box 19, Folder 237)
    LC 71007- General, 1300-G- Moving to Jackson Lake Lodge/Colter Bay
    - Cabin Plan (construction drawing), 1947 July; 2003:104:020 (Folder 9)
    - Jackson Lake Lodge Food Bar construction drawing, circa 1949; 2003:104:019 (Folder 9)
  - Post Office, 1949-1956 (Box 19, Folder 238)
    1007- General 1300-G- Moving to JLL/Colter Bay
  - Promotional Material, 1965, circa 1990s (Box 19, Folder 239)
  - Publications, 1948-1949, 1955, 1960, 1972, 1991, undated (Box 19, Folder 240)
    - Printed Press Photos, 1948 January- February; 2003:104:027 (Folder 9)
  - Publicity: General, 1948-1951, 1965, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 241)
  - Publicity: Films, 1960-1962, undated (Box 19, Folder 242)
  - Publicity: Spencer's Mountain, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 243)
  - Reimbursement Schedule, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 244)
  - Sales (Agencies), 1952 (Box 19, Folder 245)
  - Salt Lake City Office, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 246)
    517
  - San Francisco Hotel Operations (Comparisons), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 247)
  - Square G Ranch: General, 1934, 1939-1940, 1951-1955 (Box 20, Folder 248)
    202 b
  - Square G Ranch: Gros Ventre Enterprise, Inc., 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 249)
    202 c
  - Square G Ranch: Personnel, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 250)
  - Square G Ranch: Store and Gas, 1948-1953 (Box 20, Folder 251)
    1003
  - Teton County, Wyoming, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 252)
    The Problem of Teton County, Wyoming. Report by Philip H. Cornick and Robert H. Kirkwood, Institute of Public Administration, on problems resulting from transfer of land from private ownership to the GTNP.
  - Transportation
    - General, 1936-1946, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 253)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 254)
      901
    - Free Pass Authorization, 1953-1960 (Box 20, Folder 255)
      905
    - Gillette Contract, 1948-1956 (Box 20, Folder 256)
      901 A
    - Idaho Public Service Commission, 1948-1952 (Box 20, Folder 257)
      901 E
    - Idaho Public Service Commission, 1952-1958 (Box 20, Folder 258)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission Agreements (Correspondence), 1947-1956 (Box 21, Folder 259)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission Agreements (F.C. Gillette and W.J. Haynes), 1946-1951 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission Certificate, 1950-1956 (Box 21, Folder 261)
      901 C
    - Jennings National Park Service Permit, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - Jennings National Park Service Permit, 1948-1956 (Box 21, Folder 263)
      901 F
    - Public Utilities Commission, 1948-1952, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 264)
    - Rates and Schedules, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 265)
      LC 25
    - Sales Tours, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 266)
    - Victor-Moran Line, 1952-1955 (Box 21, Folder 267)
    - Wyoming Contract Permit, 1951-1956 (Box 21, Folder 268)
      902 B
    - Wyoming Public Service Commission, 1947-1955 (Box 21, Folder 269)
    - Wyoming Public Service Commission (Special Hearing), 1953-1956 (Box 21, Folder 270)
      901 D
  - Tree Planting Program, 1946-1950 (Box 22, Folder 271)
  - Vehicles, 1950-1954 (Box 22, Folder 272)
    Folder originally entitled "Personal Property (Autos)," file number 252. A few items for 1952 added from folder "Operations - Autos and Trucks"
  - Visits: John F. Kennedy, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Still Images of John F. Kennedy's visit to Grand Teton National Park, 1963 September; 2003:104:024 (Box 29)
  - Visits: Lady Bird Johnson, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Still Images of Lady Bird Johnson's Visit to Grand Teton National Park, 1964 August 14-17; 2003:104:025 (Box 29)
    - Still images and negatives of Lady Bird Johnson's visit to Grand Teton National Park, 1964 August 14-17; 2003:104:026; 2 folders- one for still images, one for negatives (Box 29)
  - Wyoming Secretary of State, 1949-1953 (Box 22, Folder 275)
- Corporate Financial Records, 1934-1985; 3; 3 Cubic Feet 6 boxes
  Series arranged alphabetically.
  The Corporate Financial series includes a full run of financial statements and/or audit reports for 1934-1985, as well as various investment, stockholder, and tax records.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 22, Folder 276)
  - Financial Statements and Audit Reports
    - 1934-1939 (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - 1940-1946 (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 279)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 281)
    - 1954 (Box 23, Folder 282)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 283)
    - 1957 (Box 23, Folder 284)
    - 1958 (Box 23, Folder 285)
    - 1959 (Box 23, Folder 286)
    - 1960 (Box 23, Folder 287)
    - 1961 (Box 23, Folder 288)
    - 1962 (Box 24, Folder 289)
    - 1963 (Box 24, Folder 290)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 24, Folder 291)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 292)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 293)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 294)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 295)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 296)
    - 1975-1978 (Box 25, Folder 297)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 298)
    - 1982-1985 (Box 25, Folder 299)
  - Investments, 1958-1960 (Box 25, Folder 300)
  - Investments, 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 301)
  - Ledgers, 1947-1950, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 302)
    Ledger page (Coupon Accounts Receivable), pertaining to travel companies and tours; check register - payments to Underwood and others concerning Jackson Lake Lodge construction, 1953-1954
  - Stocks
    - GTLC Stockholders: Minutes, 1954, 1956, 1959, 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 303)
    - GTLC Stockholders: Minutes, 1965-1966, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 304)
    - Stock Certificates, 1952-1956 (Box 26, Folder 305)
    - Stock Certificates, 1957-1963 (Box 26, Folder 306)
    - Stock Certificates, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 307)
    - Stock Certificates, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 307 A)
      Restricted material.
    - Stock Certificates: Teton Investment Company Transfer, 1936-1937 (Box 26, Folder 308)
    - Stockholder Record, 1936-1949 (Box 26, Folder 309)
  - Taxes
    - Federal Excise, 1952-1957 (Box 26, Folder 310)
    - Federal Excise, 1958-1962 (Box 26, Folder 311)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1952-1955 (Box 26, Folder 312)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 313)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 314)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1960-1962 (Box 26, Folder 315)
    - Federal Taxes, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 316)
      502
    - Federal Withholding Tax, 1951-1957 (Box 27, Folder 317)
      502 C
      Restricted- Confidential material
    - Federal Withholding Tax, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 318)
      Restricted- Personnel Information
    - Federal Withholding Tax, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 319)
    - Federal Withholding Tax, 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 320)
    - Property Taxes, 1952-1955, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 321)
    - Utah State Tax Commission, 1947-1955 (Box 27, Folder 322)
      - Certificate of Incorporation, 1947 October 30; 2003:104:021 (Folder 9)
    - Wyoming Poll Tax, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 323)
    - Wyoming State Sales Tax, 1951-1956 (Box 27, Folder 324)
- Grand Teton Lodge Company Photographs, 1954-1989; 4
  Photographs
  - Colter Bay and Jackson Lake Lodge Construction, circa 1954-1956; Approximately 200 still images (Box 28, Folder 325)
  - Unidentified Photos (Box 29, Folder 326)
    - Still image of Cabins
    - Still image of man with horse
      General
      Photo found loose in box.
      Writing on back- "Among Harold Fabian papers?"
    - Still image of Vernon Johnson and Horace Albright
  - Board of Directors, circa 1970s - 1980s; 1 still image (Box 29, Folder 327)
    Group photo, including: Franklin E. Parker, Fred J. Eydt, Clifford P. Hansen, Bernie Iliff, Nash Castro, Fred Smith, Clayton W. Frye, Jr., John D. Green, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Carlisle H. Humelsine, Charles H. P. Duell, Richard E. Holtzman, Felix Buckenroth, Jr.
  - Colter Bay, circa 1954-1955; 3 still images (Box 29, Folder 328)
  - Jackson Lake Lodge, circa 1954-1955; 15 still images (Box 29, Folder 329)
  - Jackson Lake Lodge, circa 1962-1964, 1976; 26 black and white still images 5 color still images 4 contact photo sheets 1 transparency 3 Post cards and map of Jackson Lake Lodge remodeling (Box 29, Folder 330)
  - Moran and Jackson Lake Lodge (transparencies), 3 black and white transparencies of Moran cabins 1 color transparency of Jackson Lake Lodge (Box 29, Folder 331)
  - Separated Photographs
    - 2 pictures of Construction at Jackson Lake Lodge, 1960 October 29; 2003:104:001 (Box 29, Folder 332)
      Separated Materials
      Separated From: Box 1/ Folder 8 GTLC Board of Directors: Agenda, 1960-1961
    - 4 pictures of remodeling at Jackson Lake Lodge, 1961 October 29; 2003:104:002 (Box 29, Folder 333)
      Separated From: Box 1/ Folder 8 GTLC Board of Directors:Agenda, 1960-1961
    - 6 negatives of Jackson Lake Lodge, circa 1954; 2003:104:007 (Box 29, Folder 334)
      Separated From: Box 13/ Folder 148 GTLC Jackson Lake Lodge: Furnishings (3), 1954
    - Photo of rifle, 1956 April 20; 2003:104:016 (Box 29, Folder 335)
      Separated From: Box 17/ Folder 209 GTLC New York Office: Chorley, Kenneth (Correspondence), 1956
    - Still Images of John F. Kennedy's visit to Grand Teton National Park, September 1963; 2003:104:024 (Box 29, Folder 336)
      Separated from: Box 22/ Folder 273 GTLC: Visits (John F. Kennedy), 1963
    - Still Images of Lady Bird Johnson's visit to Grand Teton National Park, 1964 August 14-17; 2003:104:025 (Box 29, Folder 337)
      Separated from: Box 22/ Folder 274 GTLC: Visits (Lady Bird Johnson), 1964
    - Still Images and Negatives of Lady Bird Johnson's visit to Grand Teton National Park, 1964 August 14-17; 2003:104:026; Still Images- Folder 338 Negatives- Folder 339 (Box 29, Folder 339, Folder 338)